BIRIR SOSPETER

WEB DEVELOPER & CYBER SEC EXPERT

- **2** 0701616456
- sospeterbirir1@gmail.com
- nairobi,Kenya
- birir-portfolio.netlify.app

SKILLS

- Networking Devices Configuration
- Workstation Setup
- Software Development (PHP, Larayel)
- Graphic Design
- ICT Security
- Marketing Strategy

EDUCATION

SECONDARY SCHOOL

Newlight Group of Schools.

2016 - 2019

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Pioneer International University.

2020 - 2023

PROFILE

Certified penetration tester and cybersecurity expert with proficiency in PHP, Laravel, and graphic design. Holds a BSc in ICT with a focus on Cybersecurity and Cryptography from Pioneer International University. Adaptable, continuously learning, and strategically analytical, committed to advancing cybersecurity practices.

EXPERIENCE

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER & CYBER SEC RESEARCHER.

Pioneer University.

2023 - present

- Laboratory Analysis
- Research and Development (R&D)
- Cyber Threat Intelligence (CTI)
- Digital Publishing

WEB DEVELOPER.

tovu sacco.

2022 - 2023

- Web Development
- Digital Marketing
- Upgradation
- Information Technology Infrastructure

ATTACHEE

Nairobi City Water and Sewerage Company.

2023 jan - april

- Presentation Skills
- Data Analysis
- Technical Writing
- Data Entry

BIRIR SOSPETER

PROFILE



@sospeterbirir



@sospeterbirir



@sospeterbirir



+254 701616456

INTEREST

- · Cybersecurity enthusiast
- Certified penetration tester in PHP, Laravel, and graphic design
- - System optimization enthusiast
- Continuous learner for evolving IT challenges
- Ready to contribute to a secure digital future

REFFEREES

Dr Wilfred Odoyo ,Director Research and Innovations, Pioneer International University, Wilfred.Odoyo@piu.ac.ke 0742150381.

Matthew Orata, ICT Officer, Nairobi City Water and Sewerage Company. 0724010434.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To leverage my expertise as a certified penetration tester and cybersecurity specialist, coupled with proficiency in PHP, Laravel, and graphic design, in a dynamic professional environment. Seeking a challenging role to contribute to cutting-edge projects, advance cybersecurity practices, and continuously enhance skills in an evolving technological landscape.

PERSONAL DETAILS.

- Nationality: Kenyan.
- Religion: Christian.
- Languages: English, Kiswahili and German.
- Portfolio: Birir-portfolio.netlify.app.

EXTRA SKILL

- Certified Driver: East African Community Drivers Lisence.
- Photography.
- Sales and Marketing.

DEVELOPMENT.

- Goal Oriented.
- Team Player.